Will you look at that? The color is perfect too.
你看 颜色非常合适
It matches your complexion.
很衬你的肤色
I can't wait till you try it on.
我很期待看你穿上它的那一天
It's the color of cherry blossoms, like the kimono my mother used to wear.
是和母亲的和服很相似的樱花色
It suits you very well. Don't you think so, Young Master?
非常适合你 对吧 少爷?
But sir?
不过老爷
I can't possibly take all of these nice pieces of kimono.
这么好的和服 我不能收这么多
It's to say thanks for the hair string. Just accept them.
是发绳的回礼 收下就好
Okay.
好的
It was Mr. Kudo himself who chose this pattern for you.
这是久堂先生自己为您选的样式
I'm happy for you, Ms. Miyo.
真是太好了 美世小姐
Yes.
是
Thank you very much.
非常感谢您
MY HAPPY MARRIAGE
剧名:我的幸福婚约
EPISODE 5 RIPPLES
第5集:风浪
I never thought she would win the heart of Kudo.
没想到她能赢得久堂先生的心
That's quite a feat.
真是了不得
Mr. Tatsuishi, is that some kind of joke?
叔叔 您到底在说什么玩笑话?
It's no joke. It's the truth about your older sister.
不是玩笑 是令姐的事
Don't you want to know how Miyo is doing now?
你不想知道她现在在做什么吗?
That man...
这个人是...
It's the man I saw that time.
是那时看到的人
As you can see...
如你所见
Miyo is getting along well with Kiyoka Kudo.
美世和久堂清霞相处得很好
This man is Kiyoka Kudo?
这个人是久堂清霞大人?
I still can't believe his bride will be that girl, Miyo.
没想到他的妻子将会是那个美世
Honestly, it's causing a problem with our plan.
说实话 对于我们来说也很头疼
- We wanted her to be Kazushi's wife. -I won't forgive her!
-我们想让她嫁给一志 -不能原谅
Shinichi didn't want you, his beloved daughter,
真一也不希望你这个宝贝女儿
to marry into a family with a bad reputation like the Kudo family, I'm sure.
嫁给臭名昭著的久堂家
I'm going to go ask Father.
我会去请求父亲大人
You're concerned too, aren't you?
叔叔您也很头疼吧?
Y-Yes.
是啊
Leave it to me. My father can't say no to me.
交给我吧 父亲向来对我有求必应
What a foolish girl.
真是个愚蠢的女孩
Thanks to her, I don't need to do anything.
多亏了她 我不必出手了
My husband-to-be arranged for me to have a meeting with Hana.
多亏了老爷 我再次和花见面
To show my gratitude,
为了表示我的感激
I decided to have a dinner party
我打算邀请帮忙的五道大人
and invite Mr. Godo as well.
做一桌好菜款待他
Boy, am I excited to see Ms. Miyo again!
能再次见到美世小姐 真是太好了
You'd better behave yourself.
你不要得意忘形
Aren't you on night patrol from tomorrow?
你明天起要在夜间巡逻吧
Wow, Ms. Miyo's cooking...
美世小姐亲手制作的料理
Don't say her name like that!
不要叫得那么亲热
Why? Are you jealous?
什么?你是吃醋了吗?
Of course not.
当然不是
I just had a momentary urge for violence.
只是一瞬间怒上心头 想使用暴力
Which is basically jealousy.
这就是吃醋
Did you say something?
你说什么?
Uh, no, nothing.
什么都没有
Ready.
做好了
Hurry up and get out!
快下车
Hey, you don't have to be so rough!
你不要这么粗暴啊
I'll tell Ms. Miyo on you!
我要跟美世小姐告状
Ow...
好疼啊
It's all right if you disappear now.
你就这么消失也可以
Give me a break...
饶了我吧
Welcome home, sir.
欢迎回家 老爷
Whoa, Ms. Miyo!
是美世小姐
Mr. Godo, welcome to our home too.
欢迎你来 五道大人
Wow.
天啊
You look especially beautiful today.
你今天真的特别漂亮
Sir, I...
老爷 我...
You're so... beautiful.
你很美
You look good in that kimono.
这件和服很适合你
Maybe I should go home after all.
要不我还是回去吧
Please come in.
请进
Big Sister, happier than me?
姐姐比我还幸福?
I will never...
我不许这种事发生
ever allow it.
绝对不可以
Thank you for the meal!
我开吃了
It's delicious!
太好吃了
It's really good!
真的太好吃了
Please help yourself.
不要客气
To think of being able to eat Ms. Miyo's delicious cooking every day!
一想到能每天吃到美世小姐做的 这么美味的料理
I'm jealous of you, Commander.
我还真是羡慕队长
Oh, I want to try this too.
我要吃吃看这个
So good!
好吃
Mr. Godo, shall I pour you some?
五道大人 我给您倒一些吧?
Oh, thank you very much.
好的 多谢
Mr. Godo, thank you for helping me meet with Hana the other day.
五道大人 前些天 多谢您带花来
But you did use your precious time for somebody like me.
但为了我这样的人 占用了您宝贵的时间
I truly appreciate your kindness.
我非常感谢您
Ms. Miyo! I'm happy because nobody has ever said anything like this to me before!
美世小姐 从来没有人 对我这么说过 我很开心
Why don't you leave the fiendish commander and marry me?
你干脆和这个恶鬼队长分手 嫁给我吧
Godo! What the hell?!
五道 你这个家伙
I'm just kidding.
我只是开玩笑的
Um, Mr. Godo.
五道大人
I appreciate your offer,
很感谢您这么说
but I prefer my husband-to-be.
不过我有老爷就好
I'm so sorry.
对不起
I didn't think you'd take it seriously...
没想到你这么认真地回复我
I guess the fiendish commander is a human after all.
恶鬼队长也是人啊
Did you say something?
你说什么了吗?
Uh, no, nothing.
没什么
Good grief. He definitely had too much to drink.
真是的 那家伙喝多了
And he's aware that it's going to get busy.
他明知接下来会忙碌
Was this dinner a problem for you?
给您添麻烦了吗?
No, no. It's not that.
不 不是的
Well, it was surprising when you said you wanted to invite Godo for dinner.
不过听你说你想款待五道时 我确实很吃惊
Were you able to accomplish what you wanted?
你想做的事都实现了吗?
Yes.
是的
Thanks to you, I was able to show my gratitude to Mr. Godo.
多亏了您 我能对五道大人表达谢意
Thank you very much.
谢谢您
Why?
为什么?
It doesn't matter.
没有为什么
Forget about Miyo.
忘掉美世吧
But I'm the one more worthy to marry into the Kudo family.
可我才是更应该嫁入久堂家的那个人
You just can't.
你不可以
Why?
为什么?
Why won't you listen to what I have to say?
为什么你不肯听我说?
Kaya. If you have too much free time,
香耶 如果你这么闲
be good and go do some training to become a good wife.
就老老实实做新娘功课去吧
Father!
父亲大人
You're different from her. You must always be superior to her.
你和她不一样 你必须比她更好
Koji?
幸次?
Huh?
什么?
Why are you here this late at night?
你这么晚来干什么?
Listen, Koji.
听我说 幸次
Wouldn't you rather get engaged to Big Sister?
你不想和姐姐订婚吗?
- Help... - Help me...
-救我 -救救我
- Stay away... - Help...
-不要过来
Help...
救救我
Think about what you did. Don't show your face until you're sorry.
在你反省过自己的错误之前 不要出现在我面前
Miyo.
美世
Remnants of supernatural ability...?
异能的残留吗?
But there's no sign of the barrier being broken.
可是结界并没有破坏的迹象
What does it mean?
这是怎么回事?
I'm so...
十分...
sorry.
抱歉
Miyo, wake up!
美世 醒醒
Are you all right?
你没事吧?
Huh? Sir?
什么?老爷?
You were groaning in your sleep.
你在睡中呻吟
Were you having a bad dream or something?
是做了噩梦吗?
A dream...
梦...
You don't have to force yourself to remember.
不用勉强自己想起来
If anything unusual occurs, don't hesitate to tell me.
要是有怪事发生 不必顾虑告诉我
Okay.
好的
Remember.
你记住
No matter what happens,
不管发生了什么
I will always be there for you.
我都会赶到你身边
Understood, sir.
我知道了 老爷
Wouldn't you rather get engaged to Big Sister?
你不想和姐姐订婚吗?
Mr. Tatsuishi said he'll cooperate.
辰石叔叔说他会帮忙
You'll cooperate too, of course, right?
你也会帮忙的 不是吗?
There, done.
做好了
He's going to be so happy.
少爷肯定会很高兴的
The Young Master tends not to bother with meals when he's busy.
他们忙起来嫌吃饭麻烦
He's probably famished by now.
现在应该很饿吧
I hope he doesn't mind me going to his workplace.
希望他不会觉得我叨扰他的工作
It'll be all right.
没事的
As soon as you're ready, we should bring these to him together.
等你准备好了 我们一起拿给他
Yes.
好的
Ms. Miyo?
美世小姐
Why don't you bring this drawstring pouch today?
手提包用这个怎么样?
It's pretty.
很漂亮
I think you should use it.
机会难得 请用这个吧
The Young Master would love to see it.
少爷应该会高兴
I will use it. Thank you.
好的 谢谢您
Okay then, shall we go?
那么让我们出发吧
I think we should hurry a bit,
不能错过午饭时间
so as not to be late for lunchtime.
我们要抓紧时间
Y-Yes.
好的
Father. Do you have a minute?
父亲 你有空吗?
Yes, what is it?
嗯 什么事?
Oh, Koji.
是你 幸次
Kaya.
香耶
Why are you here?
你为什么在这里?
Why?
说什么“为什么”
I'm here to trade fiancés with Big Sister.
我是来替换姐姐的未婚夫
Will you stop kidding around?
能不能不要说傻话?
Kidding? I'm not kidding.
什么叫“说傻话”?
I know you like Big Sister better than me.
比起我 你更喜欢姐姐吧?
Your father didn't give permission, right?
令尊并不同意吧?
There's no way it would happen without his consent.
没有他的允许 这是不可能的
But what if Big Sister herself agrees to it?
那如果姐姐自己同意了呢?
What are you up to?
你想做什么?
Well, you'll see. Just trust me.
你会知道的 我不会害你
All you have to do is watch.
你看着就好
Miyo. Yurie.
美世、由里江
Good day, sir.
老爷 您辛苦了
Sorry to bother you at work.
给您添麻烦了真不好意思
Well, I was worried you hadn't eaten properly.
但我很担心您是否有好好吃饭
So I brought you lunch.
所以我带午饭来了
Oh, right.
这样啊
That's helpful.
多谢你
It must have been tough walking here under the blazing sun.
阳光这么强烈的天气 走过来肯定很辛苦吧?
Do you want to take a rest inside?
要不要去里面休息一下?
No thank you.
不用了
I appreciate it, but I don't want to be in your way, so I'll go home.
多谢您费心 但是我不想打扰您工作
Okay.
好吧
We'll be going, then.
那我们告辞了
Miyo, do you have the amulet with you?
美世 你带护身符了吗?
Yes, I have it in here.
是的 我带在身上了
Good.
这样啊
I just wanted to make sure.
拿着就好
Commander Kudo!
久堂队长
I'll be right there!
我现在就来
I would have liked to drive you home, but I don't have time at the moment.
我本应该送你回家 但现在没有时间
It's okay.
没关系
I'm sorry to have bothered you when you're busy.
很抱歉在您繁忙的时候打扰您
No worries. Take care going home, you two.
没关系 你们俩回去的时候要小心
The Young Master was being shy, wasn't he?
少爷是害羞了呢
Ms. Miyo? What's the matter?
美世小姐 怎么了?
Well, I... um...
那个 我...
I seemed to have left the amulet at home.
我好像把护身符忘在家里了
Oh dear!
这可不好
It must be because I rushed you.
是我催你太急了吧
No, I was not mindful enough.
不 是我自己不小心
I promised him I would always bring it with me.
我答应他随身带着
Ms. Miyo, we must go straight home, without delay.
那美世小姐 我们直接回家吧
Yes.
好
I can't believe I messed up.
我真是没用
That was a precious amulet that he gave me.
老爷给我的重要的护身符
I was so excited about my new pouch that I forgot about the amulet.
竟然因为新的手提包 得意忘形而忘带了
Ms. Yurie!
由里江阿姨
Ms. Miyo!
美世小姐
Kaya, Father, what are you trying to do to Miyo?
香耶、父亲 你们想对美世做什么?
We're going to make Big Sister turn down the marriage offer from Mr. Kudo.
我们想让姐姐回拒久堂大人的婚约
Right, Mr. Tatsuishi?
对吧 辰石叔叔?
You know we can't just stand by in this situation.
我们也不能就这样袖手旁观
Anyway, I'll be waiting for you at the Saimori house.
那么我在斋森大宅恭候
It's the only way to get that girl. I have no choice.
这是为了得到那个女孩 没有办法
After all this time? Why?
事到如今吗?为什么?
This is a matter between families.
这是家族之间的问题
Miyo being isolated in her family was beneficial to us, the Tatsuishi family.
美世当时被孤立对我们辰石家有利
What the hell...?
你说什么?
You wouldn't understand.
你是不会理解的
I would do anything for the continuance of our family.
为了家族的存续 我会不择手段
It's my duty as the head of the Tatsuishi family.
这就是作为辰石家家主的我的任务
Unforgivable...
不可原谅
So all this time...
一直以来
you looked the other way on Miyo being treated awfully
你一直对美世受难坐视不管
for your own advantage?
是为了自己的利益吗?
I won't forgive you!
我不能原谅你
Oh? Do you intend to fight me using supernatural ability?
你是想用异能跟我一决胜负吗?
I don't want to hear anything from you anymore.
我不会再听你的话
It's futile. Stop it now.
没用的 住手吧
I won't let you have your way with Miyo's life anymore!
我不会让你对美世肆意妄为
Wha...?
什么?
Impressive. I didn't know you had this much power.
没想到你竟然有这样的力量
Huh? Why won't it...?
为什么?
Move!
给我动起来
You idiot.
你这个傻瓜
There's no way a barely trained novice like you can withstand my power.
没有经过训练的异能者 是无法与我抗衡的
If you think you can defy me, stay there on the floor and sleep it off.
如果你觉得你可以与我对抗 就在那躺一会吧
Damn...
可恶
Why?
为什么?
Let's go.
我们走吧
Yes, sir.
遵命
Koji.
幸次
If you want something, you have to select the means to get it.
如果你有想要的东西 就要不择手段
You're perpetually second-rate because you never have any strategy.
你总是毫无谋划 所以才是二流人物
I am an idiot.
我是傻瓜
Are you going to face down like that
你这样脸朝下躺着
and wait for time to pass again?
是又要等时间流逝吗?
Big Brother...
兄长
Damn it.
可恶
I couldn't do anything again. I can't even win against Father.
我又什么都没做到 甚至赢不了父亲
I'm still so immature.
我还不够成熟
Then, are you going to give up?
那你要放弃吗?
Of course, it's easier not to get involved in complicated matters.
当然还是不要卷入麻烦比较轻松
But why did you stand up to him in the first place?
那你为什么要反抗父亲?
Go wash your face.
去洗洗脸
Someone is waiting for you, right?
有人在等你不是吗?
Miyo.
美世
I'm not going to give up.
我不会放弃的
I've got to save Miyo...
为了救下美世
Miyo was kidnapped?!
美世被掳走了?
I was supposed to keep an eye on her.
明明有我陪着
I'm so sorry!
非常抱歉
What about the amulet?
护身符呢?
She must have had it with her.
她应该随身带着的
Actually...
那是...
She realized she hadn't brought it with her after we left you.
和你分开之后 她意识到自己没带在身上
Ms. Miyo...
美世小姐
I know who did it, in all likelihood.
犯人十有八九是那个人
I know where Miyo must be...
我知道美世在哪里
Hey! There's no trespassing here!
这里禁止闲人入内
Let me go! I've come to meet Mr. Kudo!
让我进去 我有事要见久堂先生
Commander!
队长
Mr. Kudo!
久堂先生
I know I'm out of line to ask you something like this.
我知道我没资格拜托你
But, please.
但是求你了
I can't save Miyo alone...
我一个人救不了美世